Okay, so I'm going to do task
number 17. Here we should write a
function hasEvenEvens for the given type
signature. This is the type signature.
And this function should give us true or false
based on whether the list… a given list, I mean,
has an even amount of even numbers or not. So what
we're saying is: if we give a function this list,
it should give us false because we have one even
number. If we give it this list, it should give us
true. It has two even numbers. What about
this one? This should give false. This one?
This one… still false. No matter how many odd
numbers we add, it doesn't change anything.
And what about the empty list? Well…
this one should give us true because
it contains exactly zero even numbers,
and zero itself is an even number.
Okay, so there are multiple
approaches I'm going to show you
an intuitive solution. We're going to… I'm
going to copy it here. And we're going to
try to explain it. So, let's say the given list is
called “list”. And first, we're going to extract
the even numbers from this list. So, we don't want
all of the elements, we just want the even ones.
We do it like this. We say x is an
element from list and x is an even number.
By the way, I've seen some people do like
this. They put the even condition first,
and then they say x is an element
from the list. This doesn't work
because at this point when Haskell is doing
evaluation, it starts from top to bottom and
from left to right, and where it reads here:
okay, so you want an element x where x is even.
But we don't even know what x is at this point.
So, when Haskell reaches here, it will give you
an error message. So, the right way to do it is to
specify first that x is an element from this list,
and then you say x is even. Okay, so nice! Now
we have the even numbers from the original list.
Now let's do this. What we have here now is the
number of the even numbers from the original list.
And now it's as simple as testing whether
this number itself is even or not.
And that's it. That's the solution. Okay,
now I'm going to show you other solutions.
There are, as you can see, so many possibilities
to solve it. So, let's see this one.
Actually, let's just put it here directly
and explain it. Okay, so we
don't need this one anymore.
Okay, so what we're saying here,
basically, is: let's take the given list
and let's consider it to be two parts: the
first element (the head of the list) and
the rest of the list (which is the tail). So, we
don't know about the tail. We don't know what it
contains exactly. All we know is that
it either gives us true or false. So,
we know that hasEvenEvens of the tail could be
true or false. And depending on that we see
what will happen when we add another element,
which is, in this case, the head of the list.
So, if we have a list that gives us true, this
means it has an even number of even numbers
already, and when we add an odd number, it doesn't
change anything. In total, we're going to have
an even number of even numbers. So, it still
gives us true. But if we add an even number,
it ruins everything: now we have an odd number
of even numbers. So, it should give us false.
And what if we have a list that doesn't
fulfill this function? (which means
hasEvenEvens of the tail of the list
gives us False). So, this means this
part… the tail of the list has an odd number of
even numbers. So, adding another odd number here,
which is the head… adding this number means
now we have… So, if we added an odd number,
it doesn't change anything at all, as
we said. But if we add an even number,
now in total, we're going to have an even number
of even numbers. So, now it gives us true again.
Okay now, so let's look at the solution.
What we are basically saying here is that
the only way for our function to return true
is either when the list is empty or when we
are adding an even number to a list that
contains an odd number of even numbers, or
we are adding an odd number to a list that
contains an even number of even numbers.
Everything else should give us false. And
of course, you can write it in simpler
ways… in different ways. I'm going to show you
something exactly equivalent to this function…
another way of writing it without
guards at all. It is this one.
So, let's compare them. Let's look here. So,
what we're saying here is this could be empty
and that will give us true or this case… The same
case from here, or this case. We don't even need
to mention “true” or “false” at all because these
things here themselves are Boolean expressions and
they evaluate to Boolean (to true or false).
So, this thing here that I'm marking here
is either true or false. And this here is either
true or false. This here is either true or false.
So, we're just basically dealing with Boolean
values. And of course, you can notice that
what we are saying here is that a and b are not
allowed to be true together or false together.
This means we can even write it this way, either
the list is empty, or a and b are not equal.
And let's test it, actually. Let's see if
it works. Just give me a second, please.
Let's reload the file and let's run main.
It's working.